

ABOUT

Frontend Engineer with 5+ years of experience and a blended skillset between creative and technical. Passionate about building design systems and component libraries, fusing the gap between design and code. Experienced with e-commerce, marketing, templated CMS sites, and SaaS.

EXPERIENCE

Dropps

UX Engineer • April 2022 - August 2023

- Converted low-fidelity designs into production code for new website features as the lead frontend engineer.
- Pioneered efforts to move website code from Shopify's liquid engine over to React for greater interactivity.
- Led the migration from Material UI to Radix headless components to improve theming, accessibility, and enable server-side rendering.
- Rebuilt customer-facing subscription portal from the ground up, with a brand new single-page UI for all functionality, in less than 3 months.
- Systematized the design pattern library using Tailwind CSS and configured design tools.
- Ensured consistency between Figma and React components using Storybook.
- Backed design and 50+ A/B test initiatives with formal UX studies from Baymard and Nielsen Norman Group.
- Implemented WCAG (accessibility) best practices including ARIA roles and color contrast.

Proton.ai

Frontend Engineer • May 2021 - March 2022

- Developed new features and maintained existing functionality in Vue/Nuxt on an Al-powered SaaS sales platform for distributors.
- Collaborated with designers to conduct user research and build features to fit client needs.
- Refined best practices and code standards as Proton's second frontend engineer.

Gannett

Web Developer • March 2018 - May 2021

• Built and maintained 1,000+ templated WordPress sites.

Dallas, TX(281) 909-7514

⊘ bradenfrazer.com

bradenfrazer@gmail.com

EDUCATION

Texas A&M University

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science • 2012 – 2017 Minored in Art and Mathematics. Graduated Cum Laude.

PROJECTS

Nintendle

Word Guessing Game • React, Tailwind CSS, Zustand

Nintendle is a Wordle clone with an emphasis on Nintendothemed solutions. The dictionary of solutions was curated by hand and includes a variety of Nintendo characters, themes, locations, and concepts.

Pokedex

Pokemon Encyclopedia • React, Tailwind CSS, PokeAPI

Pokedex app based on the Pokemon series games, built in React, and sourced by the awesome PokeAPI.

Weathrr

Weather App • React, Tailwind CSS, OpenWeatherMap API

Weather conditions app built in React. The current temperature, humidity, pressure, wind speed, and conditions are pulled from OpenWeatherMap's API.

National Parks

Travel Info App • Vue, SCSS, National Park Service API

A listing of national parks located in the United States pulled from the National Park Service API.

SKILLS

Languages & Tech

TypeScript React REST APIs Git	HTML	CS	SS	SC	SS	Tailwind	CSS	JavaScript
.,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,	TypeScript		React RE		ST APIs	Git		

UI/UX

Figma	Storybook	A/B Test	ing	Design Systems	
MUI	Headless Com	ponents	WCAG / Accessibility		

Other

Photoshop Illustrator Photography Video Editing